<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-11T22:00:25+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Фilingo Blog</title><subtitle>Blog über Filingo</subtitle><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Saying Goodbye to Bajkal, Looking Ahead to Its Successor</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/saying-goodbye-to-bajkal-looking-ahead-to-its-successor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saying Goodbye to Bajkal, Looking Ahead to Its Successor" /><published>2026-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2026-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/saying-goodbye-to-bajkal-looking-ahead-to-its-successor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/saying-goodbye-to-bajkal-looking-ahead-to-its-successor.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have discontinued work on my Russian language learning web app “Bajkal”. As a result, the application has not been accessible under the domain bajkal-app.de for several months.</p>

<p>This does not mean that the project itself has come to an end. I am already working on a successor, about which I will share more details at a later point.</p>

<p><strong>Looking Back and Reasons for a Restart</strong></p>

<p>Work on “Bajkal” accompanied me for a long time. I enjoyed it greatly, and during this period I learned a lot—conceptually, in planning, design, and of course in programming. At the same time, it became increasingly clear to me over the course of development that I needed a different, better approach to build a Russian language learning app that truly matched my own expectations.</p>

<p>There were several aspects I was ultimately not satisfied with.</p>

<p>One of the first issues concerned the name and visual identity of the app. “Bajkal” was intended to evoke associations with Russian nature, and the mascot or logo—a Baikal seal—fit this idea well. Overall, however, the connection to language learning remained too abstract and insufficiently self-explanatory.</p>

<p>Second, the learning system was too rigid and too linear. My approach assigned vocabulary to a proficiency level (A1, A2, etc.), a main topic, and a subtopic. The proficiency level corresponded to a course, the main topic to a thematic area, and the subtopic to a learning deck. As a result, every word had to be assigned to a fixed deck and therefore to a fixed topic. Since words rarely belong clearly to just one topic, I was constantly faced with the choice between overly general or overly specific deck names. The decks tended to become too large, even though they ideally should have contained a manageable number of around 10 to 20 cards. With this approach, the system was hardly workable: thousands of words would have required hundreds of topics. The result was a very rigid categorization, better suited to linear learning materials such as books. For the successor, I am therefore pursuing a networked approach that is better suited to digital learning material.</p>

<p>Another issue was the closed nature of the app. When it comes to user acquisition, it becomes clear that many people are reluctant to “buy a pig in a poke.” Especially with unfamiliar applications, a mandatory registration can already be discouraging if it is not clear what to expect. Although the entry barrier for “Bajkal” was relatively low, I would like to make access even more open in the future and allow users to try the app without registering at all.</p>

<p>I was also no longer convinced by the dashboard. “Bajkal” offered an overview of due and new learning decks, as well as widgets such as a calendar and daily Russian proverbs with German translations. This was generally useful, but I want to focus the design more strongly on the learning experience itself. The calendar, while nice, ultimately felt somewhat outdated and is dispensable for me. I did like the proverbs widget, however, and it may return in a different form and at a different place.</p>

<p>Finally, the data model was also too rigid. While it was enjoyable to carefully model the various parts of speech with all their special cases and exceptions, I ultimately opted for a hybrid approach for the successor, combining fixed fields with JSONB. This results in a broader data-layer structure with stricter validation of word data before it is imported into the database.</p>

<p><strong>What Remains, New Features, and Outlook</strong></p>

<p>Despite these issues, there are many aspects I want to keep for the successor project. The public dictionary for looking up meanings and grammatical forms remains very important to me. I still aim to provide a meaningful complement to existing online Russian dictionaries. The learning deck approach using the SuperMemo algorithm will also remain largely unchanged, aside from the UI design. An overview of learning progress will likewise be part of the next version.</p>

<p>In addition, I am planning several new or significantly expanded features. In particular, I want to improve community building, gamification, and user customization. The next version will include a ranking system, as users will be able to collect points for learning and compare themselves with others. While I am generally critical of excessive gamification, it can enhance motivation and enjoyment when applied in moderation. In addition to points, users will be able to earn achievements. Users will also be able to tailor the learning experience more closely to their own needs—from choosing UI colors to defining daily learning goals. For complete beginners, I am also planning a small practice area for learning the Cyrillic alphabet.</p>

<p>These are the most important points for now. It will still take some time before the next version of my Russian learning app is released. This time, however, I want to cover at least the A1 to B2 proficiency levels from the very beginning, ideally even up to C1. If that succeeds and I am satisfied with the result, I plan to address additional areas such as grammar, listening comprehension, and audio-visual comprehension next.</p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Russian" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have discontinued work on my Russian language learning web app “Bajkal”. As a result, the application has not been accessible under the domain bajkal-app.de for several months.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Language Learning Apps Reviewed: Anki</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/language-learning-apps-reviewed-anki.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Language Learning Apps Reviewed: Anki" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/language-learning-apps-reviewed-anki</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/language-learning-apps-reviewed-anki.html"><![CDATA[<p><a class="inline-flex items-center gap-0.5 transition hover:text-accent-600 dark:hover:text-accent-200" href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anki<svg class="link-external__icon" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" aria-hidden="true">
    <path d="M18 13v6a2 2 0 0 1-2 2H5a2 2 0 0 1-2-2V8a2 2 0 0 1 2-2h6"></path>
    <polyline points="15 3 21 3 21 9"></polyline>
    <line x1="10" y1="14" x2="21" y2="3"></line>
</svg></a> is a prime example of a highly flexible learning tool. It’s not only suitable for learning Russian, but for virtually any learning goal that involves memorizing a large amount of information efficiently. This has both advantages and disadvantages.</p>

<p>The app is based on the principle of <strong>spaced repetition</strong>, meaning systematic repetition at increasing intervals—a method that is particularly effective for training long-term memory.</p>

<h2 id="what-speaks-in-favor-of-anki">What speaks in favor of Anki?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Free of charge</strong>: Anki is open source and free on almost all platforms—Windows, macOS, Linux, Android, or via the web. Only the iOS app costs a one-time fee of €29.99.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Cross-platform</strong>: Syncing between smartphone, tablet, and desktop works smoothly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Customizable</strong>: Nearly everything can be tailored—from card layout to review intervals to plugins.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Feature-rich</strong>: Audio support, keyboard input, images, cloze deletions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Community and Add-ons</strong>: An active user community provides extensions that can further expand the app’s capabilities.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="where-are-the-weaknesses">Where are the weaknesses?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Steep learning curve</strong>: Creating your own cards takes time and effort—especially when trying to build meaningful content in German for Russian. This is particularly difficult for beginners without prior knowledge.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>No built-in didactic concept</strong>: Anki provides a tool but no structured learning system. Without a strategy, it’s hard to make meaningful progress.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Quality varies</strong>: While shared decks from other users are available, their quality can vary greatly and is often hard to assess.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Limited learning mode</strong>: The app focuses exclusively on flashcards. Interactive elements beyond simple recall are not part of the concept.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>No objective feedback</strong>: While progress is tracked statistically, there is no external assessment of your level (e.g., a CEFR evaluation).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Anki is a powerful learning platform for those willing to invest time and structure into their self-study. It can also be a valuable tool for language learners.</p>

<p>However, for beginners and self-taught learners without prior knowledge or study routines, the app may be too open-ended and technical.</p>

<p><em>An overview of all reviewed language learning apps can be found <a href="">here</a>.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Russian" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anki is a prime example of a highly flexible learning tool. It’s not only suitable for learning Russian, but for virtually any learning goal that involves memorizing a large amount of information efficiently. This has both advantages and disadvantages.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Language Learning Apps: Learning Russian Interactively</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/language-learning-apps-learning-russian-interactively.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Language Learning Apps: Learning Russian Interactively" /><published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/language-learning-apps-learning-russian-interactively</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/language-learning-apps-learning-russian-interactively.html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning Russian is a real challenge. Thanks to the wide range of digital tools available today, foreign languages seem more accessible than ever. But which apps and platforms truly deliver on their promises—and which are actually suitable for self-study?</p>

<p>In the upcoming posts in this series, I will take a detailed look at individual apps and platforms and put them to the test—from features and usability to pricing. The focus will be on <strong>interactive learning tools</strong>, meaning apps and platforms that actively involve the user in the learning process.</p>

<p>Another requirement is that the offering must be aimed at a <strong>German-speaking audience</strong>. That is, the source language of the content must be German. An overview of the tools already reviewed can be found in the table below.</p>

<h2 id="reviewed-language-learning-apps">Reviewed Language Learning Apps</h2>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Product</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Russian Focus</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Cost</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Platform</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="">Anki</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">No</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">No (except iOS)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">all</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Russian" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Russian is a real challenge. Thanks to the wide range of digital tools available today, foreign languages seem more accessible than ever. But which apps and platforms truly deliver on their promises—and which are actually suitable for self-study?]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning X: Summary</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-X-resueme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning X: Summary" /><published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-X-resueme</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-X-resueme.html"><![CDATA[<p>To conclude this introduction to my thoughts on the topic of “Digital Learning,” I’d like to summarize the key points:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Due to the extensive and cost-effective ability of computers to store, process, retrieve, and display data, <strong>digital learning materials are superior to analog ones in certain cases</strong>—particularly when it comes to delivering relatively simple, repetitive, or niche knowledge.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In the realm of educational software, <strong>specialization is generally better than openness</strong>. Anki is a prime example of an open system: it’s free, available on all platforms, but it doesn’t provide learning material suited to any particular domain.</p>

    <p>(One should remember, though, that nothing comes truly “free.” Even a free program like Anki requires development and maintenance.)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A specialized learning application must provide content created by <strong>experts in the relevant domain</strong>, optimally support the user’s learning process (through interactivity and multisensory design), offer <strong>clear feedback on user input</strong>, and still be available on <strong>all major operating systems</strong>.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To conclude this introduction to my thoughts on the topic of “Digital Learning,” I’d like to summarize the key points:]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning IX: The Domain Problem</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-ix-the-domain-problem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning IX: The Domain Problem" /><published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-ix-the-domain-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-ix-the-domain-problem.html"><![CDATA[<p>If you were choosing a restaurant to eat sushi:<br />
Which would you prefer?<br />
One that serves <strong>only sushi</strong>, or one that also offers pizza, burgers, and pasta?</p>

<p>If you place particular value on <strong>authentic sushi</strong>, you’d probably opt for the first.<br />
One could at least assume that it has a chef who specializes in preparing sushi.</p>

<p>A restaurant offering multiple cuisines, on the other hand, aims to appeal to as many tastes as possible.<br />
And unless there’s some kind of super-chef behind the scenes, the sushi likely won’t stand out among the other dishes.</p>

<p>The same idea applies to the development of educational software—and is known as the <strong>domain problem</strong>.<br />
A <em>domain</em> is, simply put, the <strong>specialized subject area</strong> an application is designed for.</p>

<p>In concrete terms, this means that while programmers are experts in their own domain (programming),<br />
they don’t necessarily have domain knowledge in the subject area they’re building software for—for example, language training.</p>

<p>Companies that want to develop and market such learning applications are therefore dependent on acquiring and implementing <strong>expert knowledge</strong>,<br />
which creates a <strong>tension between business goals and user needs</strong>.</p>

<p>The company wants to build and sell a product profitably.<br />
The user wants a cost-effective application tailored to their needs.</p>

<p>Now, imagine a company developing a language trainer for <strong>20 different languages</strong>.<br />
Their goal is to attract as many customers as possible—so it’s likely they cut corners on domain expertise.</p>

<p>You wouldn’t hold high expectations for an app meant equally for Chinese and English learners—<br />
just like you wouldn’t expect outstanding sushi at a restaurant that also serves burgers and pasta.</p>

<p>Languages can differ enormously.<br />
To meet the demands of serious language study, one must treat <strong>language training</strong> as its own domain,<br />
with <em>English language training</em> as one domain, <em>Chinese language training</em> as another, and so on.</p>

<p>As I noted earlier regarding books, <strong>quantity and quality are negatively correlated</strong>.<br />
The more general and wide-ranging an application is, the more diluted its individual parts tend to be.</p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you were choosing a restaurant to eat sushi: Which would you prefer? One that serves only sushi, or one that also offers pizza, burgers, and pasta?]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning VIII: Apps</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-viii-apps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning VIII: Apps" /><published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-viii-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-viii-apps.html"><![CDATA[<p>A third way to learn a foreign language using a program is through <strong>specialized apps or web apps</strong>.<br />
These are characterized by their use of modern web technologies.</p>

<p>This means the learning applications are accessed via a browser (and sometimes also available as native apps).<br />
To use them, you only need a relatively recent device with an internet connection.</p>

<p>It is typical for these apps to present language learning as an experience that is primarily meant to be <strong>enjoyable</strong> for the learner.<br />
In this sense, companies attract users with a wide selection of languages, bright colors, and special effects.</p>

<p>Elements of <strong>gamification</strong> make the learning process highly interactive, and built-in audio or video materials make it synesthetic.<br />
It’s understandable that companies choose to market their apps this way.</p>

<p>By doing so—and by offering as many languages as possible—they aim to appeal to a <strong>mass audience</strong>.<br />
But the truth is: this very decision almost guarantees disappointment.</p>

<p>Gamified elements can be motivating for beginners.<br />
But anyone who seriously wants to learn a foreign language will eventually realize that it’s a long and challenging process—at least for most people.</p>

<p>What’s more, languages differ significantly from one another and come with their own unique demands.<br />
An app that aims to cover as many languages as possible will <strong>necessarily sacrifice specialization</strong>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A third way to learn a foreign language using a program is through specialized apps or web apps. These are characterized by their use of modern web technologies.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning VII: Openness</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-vii-openness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning VII: Openness" /><published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-vii-openness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-vii-openness.html"><![CDATA[<p>A free alternative to the Langenscheidt vocabulary trainer that is available on multiple operating systems is the flashcard program <strong>Anki</strong>.</p>

<p>This already suggests that Anki isn’t just suited for language learning, but for virtually any kind of content that can be represented on flashcards.</p>

<p>Unlike the Langenscheidt vocabulary trainer, Anki is “just” a platform and doesn’t provide any learning content itself.<br />
Users have to create their own flashcards or rely on decks shared by others.</p>

<p>As with the Langenscheidt trainer, the quality of third-party content can vary.</p>

<p>When learning a foreign language, it’s very helpful that Anki allows you to add audio recordings (synesthetic learning).<br />
However, due to Anki’s openness to all types of learning content, the program is barely interactive.</p>

<p>Users have to decide for themselves whether they recalled a word’s translation correctly, and input the result accordingly.<br />
Just like traditional vocabulary notebooks, this requires a certain level of discipline.</p>

<p>Anki is therefore an open learning program because:</p>

<ul>
  <li>it comes with no built-in content,</li>
  <li>it doesn’t prescribe a specific type of content,</li>
  <li>it is available on multiple operating systems.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A free alternative to the Langenscheidt vocabulary trainer that is available on multiple operating systems is the flashcard program Anki.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning VI: Specialization</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-vi-specialization.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning VI: Specialization" /><published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-vi-specialization</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-vi-specialization.html"><![CDATA[<p>For French or Italian, there is sufficient demand. It makes financial sense for publishers to produce linear learning materials for these foreign languages. That is no longer the case for Slavic languages.</p>

<p>So what could be more obvious than providing the learning materials online or as software, allowing them to be updated and accessed repeatedly without the need for new editions or printing costs?</p>

<p>Many have had this idea already, which is why the internet is now full of both free and paid educational materials and software — for all sorts of subjects, whether for reference or practical use.</p>

<p>When it comes to language learning, I’ve already mentioned the paid vocabulary trainer by Langenscheidt. It <em>was</em> fantastic (now only available second-hand, last updated in 2019) — with its extensive and well-organized vocabulary collections, example sentences, and audio recordings (i.e., synesthetic learning).</p>

<p>Another major plus was that you had to type in the answers by hand while learning (interactive), and do so repeatedly until they were correct.</p>

<p>Aside from the fact that the program only ran on Windows, its biggest drawback was that it offered only a few, already popular, foreign languages.</p>

<p>On the one hand, the Langenscheidt vocabulary trainer made great use of the digital medium, compared to linear learning materials.</p>

<p>On the other hand, it reflected the market situation for linear materials — which meant it still fell short when it came to less common languages.</p>

<p>While it was possible to create your own vocabulary sets or download those shared by other users, the audio recordings were then missing, and the quality of the collections could vary greatly.</p>

<p>This meant the Langenscheidt vocabulary trainer was specialized in three ways:</p>

<ul>
  <li>in terms of the scope of content per language</li>
  <li>limited to only a few (popular) languages</li>
  <li>restricted to a single supported operating system</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For French or Italian, there is sufficient demand. It makes financial sense for publishers to produce linear learning materials for these foreign languages. That is no longer the case for Slavic languages.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning V: Vocabulary</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-v-vocabulary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning V: Vocabulary" /><published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-v-vocabulary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-v-vocabulary.html"><![CDATA[<p>Vocabulary learning works especially well when it is interactive and synesthetic — that is, when it engages multiple forms of perception. That’s why learning with a vocabulary notebook during school was particularly dreadful.</p>

<p>The only interactive part was copying the vocabulary and their meanings from the textbook into a two-column table.</p>

<p>Afterwards, you’d cover one column and try to memorize the translation. After ten minutes, the word would be in your short-term memory; after two hours, it was forgotten.</p>

<p>In Latin, I remembered vocabulary best when I had to look it up during a translation or when it appeared repeatedly in the same text.</p>

<p>In English, I built my active vocabulary by watching American series and movies. English is quite forgiving in that sense, since its grammar is relatively simple and it shares many similarities with German, making the learning curve fairly gentle.</p>

<p>French, as a Romance language, was more challenging — although the familiar word roots were helpful. It was during French that I had another very positive experience with a language learning tool: the French trainer by Langenscheidt.</p>

<p>Slavic languages, however, are in a completely different league. My personal experience is limited to Russian. But due to its unfamiliar phonetics, partially different alphabet, and very few shared roots with German, I assume the learning curve for other Slavic languages is similarly steep.</p>

<p>In Russian, one occasionally encounters the influence of German culture <em>in the form</em> of corresponding loanwords. However, Slavic languages never had the same influence on German (or European) culture as Latin, French, or — today — English.</p>

<p>All of this contributes to the relative unpopularity of Slavic languages — and to the lack of sufficient learning materials.</p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vocabulary learning works especially well when it is interactive and synesthetic — that is, when it engages multiple forms of perception. That’s why learning with a vocabulary notebook during school was particularly dreadful.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Digital Learning IV: Learning by Heart</title><link href="https://blog.filingo.app/en/digital-learning-iv-learning-by-heart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Learning IV: Learning by Heart" /><published>2024-06-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-06-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-iv-learning-by-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.filingo.app/digital-learning-iv-learning-by-heart.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first positive experience I had with an online learning program was while preparing for the theoretical part of my driving test.</p>

<p>Today, there are countless apps and websites available as free online tools for driving students. But back in 2013, it was still common to buy printed booklets with the exam questions and fill them out by hand.</p>

<p>However, there was an alternative to the paper booklets: the driving theory trainer from Aral, which a classmate fortunately recommended to me. Thanks to this great site — which <a href="https://mein.aral.de/einstellungen/theorietrainer">still exists</a>, by the way — preparing for the test became much easier.</p>

<p>All I had to do was go through the question sets repeatedly until I could answer all of them by heart. This was possible because it doesn’t really matter whether a driving student understands the reasoning behind a traffic rule — what matters is simply knowing that it applies.</p>

<p>The same principle applies to learning vocabulary in a foreign language. Of course, it’s helpful when we can associate a new word with something familiar to help us remember it.</p>

<p>But such vocabulary is the exception (and the more exotic the language, the fewer such exceptions there are). In most cases, memorization is the only thing that helps.</p>]]></content><author><name>Björn Kawecki</name></author><category term="Didactics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first positive experience I had with an online learning program was while preparing for the theoretical part of my driving test.]]></summary></entry></feed>